(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-31T20:34:53.811062",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ごきげんよう どうかしたんだろ？
Good day, is something wrong?
顔を見れば一瞬でわかるよ
I can tell the moment I see your face.
千里眼千里眼？ めっそうもないです
Clairvoyance? Not at all.
退屈ガール 恵まれたいのかい
Boredom girl, do you want to be blessed?
判定は審議の連続で
Judgments are a continuous deliberation,
ヴィーナスサステイン
Venus sustain,
踊る街並み
dancing townscape.
Perfectly, Euphoria!
何でもないような言葉で泣いたりするし
Crying over such trivial words,
ほら 僕達なんて十分適度にドラマチックさ
look, we're just about moderately dramatic.
軽やかなスーパースター
A light-footed superstar,
オリオンをなぞる こんな深い夜
tracing Orion in such a deep night.
つながりたい 離れたい
Wanting to connect, wanting to part,
つまり半信半疑あっちこっち
in short, half-believing everywhere.
新未来を願う 空前絶後の
Wishing for a brand new future, unprecedented
言葉がもし、もし紡げるなら
words—if, if we could weave them,
時間が止まるよ
time would stop.
「ココデオワルハズガナイノニ」
"This shouldn't be where it ends."
最新の技術に関する盛大な発表に乾杯
Cheers to the grand announcement on cutting-edge tech.
千里眼千里眼？ 今はなんでも
Clairvoyance? Anything goes now.
退屈ガール 歌を歌うのかい
Boredom girl, are you going to sing a song?
オーディエンスは居なくたっていいのさ
It's fine even if there's no audience.
ヴィーナスサステイン 確かな感動
Venus sustain, a certain emotion.
Perfectly, Euphoria!
切っても切れないんだ いい加減そろそろわかってよ
We're inseparable, figure it out already.
さあ 右手を伸ばして 暗い闇の底 お宝を探せ
Now, reach out your right hand into the deep dark abyss and find the treasure.
軽くテンション MAX 最後に笑えるくらいの青春を
With tension maxed out, enough youth to laugh at the end.
夢を見て 恋をして あきれ返るような日々を謳歌
Dreaming, falling in love, celebrating days that make you shake your head.
ナイフを持つ その本当の意味が
The true meaning of holding a knife—
あなたにもし、もし分かるのなら
if, if you can understand it too,
すごく嬉しいんだ
I'd be so happy.
何度よろけ倒れたとしても
No matter how many times I stumble and fall,
さっき立ったんだし 立てないわけがないよ
I stood up just a moment ago, there's no way I can't stand again.
光る声は 軽くなって 宙に浮いて なるべく遠くへ
The shining voice grows lighter, floats into the sky, heading as far as possible.
オリオンをなぞる こんな深い夜
Tracing Orion in such a deep night,
つながりたい 離れたい つまり半信半疑あっちこっち
wanting to connect, wanting to part, half-believing everywhere in short.
新未来を願う 空前絶後の 言葉がもし、もし紡げるなら
Wishing for a brand new future, if we could weave unprecedented words...
ごきげんよう
How are you,
どうかしたんだろ？
did something happen?
さあ ここには歩くような
Now then, with a walking-like
テンションを 夢を見て 恋をして
tension, dreaming and falling in love...
明け方のような君を歌う
Singing of you like the dawn,
ナイフを持つその本当の意味が
holding a knife, the true meaning of it
あなたにもし もしわかるのなら すごく嬉しいんだ
if you understand it, I'd be so happy.
何度やり直そうとも
No matter how many times I redo it,
パーフェクト グロリーで パーフェクト グロリーで
with perfect glory, with perfect glory,
パーフェクト グロリーで パーフェクト グロリーがなきゃ
with perfect glory, if there's no perfect glory,
光る声は軽くなって 宙に浮いて 遥か遠くへ
The shining voice becomes lighter, floating far into the sky,
オリオンをなぞる こんな深い夜
Tracing Orion in this deep night,
しびれたい 話されたい
I want to be numb, I want to be released,
つまり半信半疑 あっちこっち 新未来を描くぜ 絶絶ごどの
half-believing here and there, drawing a new future...
言葉がもし もし紡げるなら 時間が止まるよ オリオンをなぞる こんな深い夜に
If words could be spun, time would stop. Tracing Orion in this deep night...
僕がいて あなたがいて それだけで十分だから 新未来を描くぜ 絶絶ごどの
I am here, you are here, that alone is enough. Drawing a new future...
言葉がもし もし紡げるなら 一緒に殺そうよ オリオンをなぞるこんな夜よ
If words could be spun, let's kill it together. Orion tracing night like this...
昨日までをちゃんと愛して 見たことない景色を見るよ ここで終わりなんてないのに
Loving yesterday properly, seeing scenery I've never seen before, even though there's no ending here!
はーいということで皆さん こんやぴー！常闇トワと神楽七奈でーす！イエーイ！
Hi everyone, Konya-pi! It's Tokoyami Towa and Kagura Nana! Yay!
はーいこんにちはこんばんは おはようございます！獅子神レオナ所属のVTuberは獅子神レオナです！イエーイ！
Hi, hello, good evening, good morning! I'm Shishigami Leona, a VTuber!
やばい、なんかさ、トワ様、なんか今泣きそうになったなんかすみません。
Oh no, like, Towa-sama, I almost cried just now, somehow, sorry.
なんて、なんでだって？いや、トワは、あの、レオピとね、あの、Apexとかやったことあって
Why, why is that? Well, Towa has, you know, played Apex and stuff with Leopi...
うん、そうだね。でも歌を超えてコラボするのが初めてで、
Yeah, that's right. But collaborating across songs for the first time...
そうね、初めてだわ。いやぁ、あのトワはレオピの歌ね、いっぱい聞いてて、すごい大好きなね、
That's right, it's the first time. Well, Towa listens to Leopi's songs a lot, and loves them so much...
歌歌ってるVTuberさんで、こうやって呼んで来てくれたこと、感謝します。
As a VTuber who sings, thank you for inviting me to come like this.
いやいや、呼んでいただきましてありがとうございます。で、なんかさ、パーフェクトにユーフォリアとかをさ、
No no, thank you for inviting me. And, like, 'Perfect Euphoria' and stuff...
話し合おうねみたいな。お互い送って、無縁こうしようねみたいなこと言ってて、
Let's discuss it, sending to each other, let's do this kind of connection, saying things like that.
向き合った時に、なんかトワ手寝ちゃった！
When we faced each other, somehow Towa fell asleep!
なんて！なんで寝ちゃったの？いや、嬉しいと思って愛して寝てきてくれて、ありがとう。
What! Why did you fall asleep? Well, thinking you were happy, you fell asleep, thank you.
いや、ありがとう。楽しいね、やっぱこういう盛り上がる曲はね。
Yeah, thanks. It's fun, after all, songs that get you hyped like this.
見て、てかさ、トワとさ、レオピさ、服の趣味が結構似てるよね？似てる？ちょっとアップして、アップにして。
Look, I mean, Towa and Leopi, our clothing tastes are pretty similar, right? Similar? Zoom up, zoom in.
ほら、あ、こうか。あ、いい感じ！いぇーい！
Look, ah, like this. Ah, good feeling! Yay!
いいね、いいね。じゃあね、レオピにはね、うんうん、一回バイバイしてもらうね。
Nice, nice. Then, Leopi, please say bye-bye once.
交わしたはずのない約束が 今日も僕らの未来を奪おうとする
The promises we never even made are trying to steal our future today again.
欲しがっていたものを手に入れても 素直にうまく笑えないのはなぜだろう
Even when I get what I wanted, why can't I smile honestly?
交わしたはずのない約束が
Promises that shouldn't have been exchanged
今日も 僕らの未来を奪おうとする
Will try and take away our future today, too
欲しがっていたものを手に入れても
Even if I obtain what I wanted,
素直に うまく笑えないのはなぜだろう
I wonder why I still can't smile naturally.
あふれる涙は 弱さや後悔じゃない
These overflowing tears aren't from weakness or regret,
イタミが産んだカケラで
but fragments born from pain.
どんな瞬間だって 運命だって
Whatever moment, whatever fate,
ひとつだけ確かなものがあると知った
I've learned that only one thing is certain.
ひとりであれこれ現実(いま)を迷うより
Instead of hesitating over reality alone,
明日を迎えにいこうんだ
I'm going to go greet tomorrow.
ずっと持ってたたい 心の地雷スイッチは切ってない
The landmine switch in my heart that I always held hasn't been cut off,
いつも僕を見てる ありふれたメロディがくずれないと人に笑われても
It's always watching me, even if people laugh at ordinary melodies not falling apart,
キラキラ なおさら輝くのはなぜだろう
I wonder why it sparkles even more brilliantly.
何が真実(ほんと)で嘘か リクツじゃなくて
What's the truth and what's a lie? Not with logic,
感じていたい ココロで
but with my heart, I want to feel it.
きっと愛しくだって ゲットだって ごまかしたくないよ
I'm sure it's love, or a get—I don't want to deceive it.
傷ついたとしても 分かち合いたいと強く願う
Even if I get hurt, I strongly wish to share it.
きっと愛すだって ゲットだって ごまかしたくないよ
I'm sure it's love, I'm sure it's a get, I don't want to gloss it over.
傷ついたとしても 分かち合いたいと
Even if I get hurt, I strongly wish
強く願う 泣けるくらい青空 交差点で手を伸ばした
to share it—reaching out my hand at the blue, tear-jerking intersection.
10年後もこんなふうにいられるかな 一緒に
Will we still be like this 10 years from now, together?
どんな瞬間だって 運命だって
Whatever moment, whatever fate,
ひとつだけ確かなものがあると知った
I've learned that only one thing is certain.
限界だって困難だって あきらめたくないよ
Whatever limits, whatever hardships, I don't want to give up.
このまま 離さないで かたく握りしめた
Don't let go, holding tightly onto
君の右手のエクモ(ぬくもり) ここにあるから 一緒に
The warmth of your right hand that is right here, together...
どんな瞬間だって 運命だって
Whatever moment, whatever fate,
ひとつだけ確かなものがあると知った
I've learned that only one thing is certain.
限界だって困難だって あきらめたくないよ
Whatever limits, whatever hardships, I don't want to give up.
このまま 離さないで かたく握りしめた
Don't let go, holding tightly onto
君の右手のエクモ(ぬくもり) ここにあるから
The warmth of your right hand that is right here...
はーい！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much!
2曲目は…「とわの、大事な…」
The second song is... "Towa's precious..."
大好きで、すごく尊敬してるすいちゃんが来てくれました！
The wonderful Suisei, whom I admire so much, came to join me!
星の如く現れた星の原石！アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいでーす！
A raw gem appearing like a shooting star! Idol VTuber Hoshimachi Suisei!
え、ちょっと水飲むんじゃおっかな
Um, I think I'll go drink some water.
2人で一緒に飲むと無口になるっていうね
They say when two people drink together, they go silent.
とわのね、すいちゃんの50万人記念の枠で初めてデュエットして
Towa, when we did a duet for Suisei's 500k subscriber stream for the first time...
プラトニックラブをやったの。でもとわの配信では1回もコラボしたことなかったの。
We did "Platonic Love". But on Towa's stream, we had never collaborated even once!
そうなんです。だからこうやって一緒に歌えたことがとっても嬉しい！
That's right. So today, I'm so happy we were able to sing together like this!
ちょうど最近もね、とわがギターやって、私がベースやって。
Just recently too, Towa played guitar and I played bass.
これだったらとわ、これだったら…次の日めちゃめちゃ筋肉痛になったからね！
Towa, if it's this... the next day we got so muscle sore!
このB客が筋肉痛って…
Saying this B-section gave us muscle pain...
今日も楽しかった！一緒に歌えて。もう1曲一緒に歌ってくれますか？
Today was so fun too! Singing together. Will you sing one more song with me?
仕方ないなぁ！
I suppose I have no choice!
待て待て、歌ってください、歌ってください
Wait, wait! Please sing! Please sing!
はい、はい
Yes, yes.
じゃあね、あのスイちゃんともう一曲コラボするんですが！
So, Suisei and I are going to collaborate on another song!
もう一人にも来てもらえたらと思います。
But we'd love for one more person to join us.
もう一度！来てくれるかな？
Once more! Will you come?
来てくれるかな？
Will you come?
ゆったり来ちゃったよ
I came here at a leisurely pace.
ゆっくり来すぎたよ
You came way too slowly!
ゆっくりね…待ったよ
Slowly... We waited!
待ったよ？
We waited!
遅いよ、本当にもう国盗りの…
You're so late, really, like a national conquest...
ではですね、もうこのコラボ曲は、こちらで最後になるんですけれども、
So, this collaborative song will be our last one here,
最後までみんなで盛り上がっていける？
but can everyone get hyped up until the very end?
イェーイ！盛り上がっていこう！
Yeah! Let's get hyped!
未来はオンナのためにある
The Future is for Women
冗談やめてとめて
Stop joking, cut it out,
マジでムリでどいてバカにしないで
for real, no way, get out, don't mock me!
どっちの台詞なのはよ
Whose line is that supposed to be?
アンチクショウ コンチクショウ
Damn it all, damn you all!
どっか消えておくれよ
Just disappear somewhere already,
夢泥棒 wow
dream thief, wow!
お嬢さん 羊の仮面かぶったあいつらが
Young lady, those guys wearing sheep masks
息ひそめ 狙いをさだめ ひょいと近づいてくる
holding their breath, locking on their target, sneaking up close.
カンチガイ野郎は面の皮が厚いからハートの痛みもわからない
Deluded bastards have thick skin and don't even know heartaches.
あなた（あなた）好みの女（なんて）
A woman of your (your) liking (as if!)—
笑わせないでよ
don't make me laugh!
ほらね（ほらね）うわさ通りのろくでなしだから
See? (See?) Just as rumors say, you're good-for-nothing,
女たちよ 声をあげよう 続けよう
So women, let's raise our voices and keep going!
たった一つだけしか真実はないのよ
There is only one single truth!
からん ハラハラして ふらふらせて
Clang, feeling anxious and dizzy,
惚れぼれしちゃう 乙女のウブが
making a maiden's innocent heart swoon—
けしてけして 許しはしないはずさ
we surely will never, ever forgive that!
台無しなんて言わせない 狂わせたってかまわない
Don't you dare ruin it, I don't care if it drives you crazy!
冗談やめてとめて マジでムリでどいてバカにしないで
Stop joking, cut it out, for real, no way, get out, don't mock me!
お姉さん こんがかった罠にハマってない？
Big sis, aren't you caught in a tangled trap?
飴玉のような嘆きと 無理みたいな洗脳と
With candy-like sighs and impossible brainwashing,
いくじなしヤロウは焼きもち焼きの嘘つきだわ
cowards are just jealous liars!
ナミダの意味さえわからない
You don't even know the meaning of tears.
おまえ（おまえ）独り占めだね（なんて）
Trying to keep me (me) all to yourself (as if!)—
出直しに来てよ
come back when you've rethought it!
あのね（あのね）明後日おいでのおかじすとだから
You see, (You see,) you're just an egoist who only thinks of himself,
女たちよ 自由になあれ 鎖をほどいて
So women, be free and break your chains!
たった一度だけしか人生はないから
Because you only get one life.
見せて ぞくぞくして くらくさせて
Show me, thrilling and dizzying,
虜にしちゃう シビル覚悟
a captivating, shivering resolve!
きっときっと うねりに変わるはずさ
Surely, surely it will turn into a massive wave!
どこまでだって感じたい どこまでだって愛したい
I want to feel it to the absolute limit, I want to love to the very end!
冗談やめてとめて マジでムリでどいてバカにしないで
Stop joking, cut it out, for real, no way, get out, don't mock me!
女たちよ 自由に誰 鎖をほどいて
Women, free yourselves, untie the chains!
たった一度だけしか人生はないから
Because you only live once.
見せて ぞくぞくして くらくさせて
Show me, thrill me, make me dizzy,
虜にしちゃう痺れる覚悟
a mesmerizing, numbing resolve!
胸にに変わるはずは 感じたい
Surely turning into a wave, I want to feel—
冗談やめてとめて マジでムリでどいてバカにしないで
Stop joking, cut it out, for real, no way, get out, don't mock me!
一人では 小さな声 かき消されてしまうけど
Alone, a small voice might get drowned out,
時代こえ 集まれば 未来は
but if we gather across the ages, the future
すべて 私たちのためにあるだから
is entirely for us! Therefore...
街のイルミ キラキラキラ
The town's illuminations sparkle, sparkle
門限とっくに過ぎてるけど
My curfew passed long ago, but
あと少し、あと少しだけ
Just a little more, just a little more
今夜は背伸びしたい気分
Tonight I'm in the mood to act a bit more grown-up
新しいワンピ 甘いリップ
A new dress, sweet lips
コーデもバッチリ決まったし
My outfit is put together perfectly, too
怒られたときの言い訳より
Rather than making excuses when I get scolded
お気に入りヒール鳴らし踊ってたいの
I want to dance, making my favorite heels click
もっとあたしを見て ママには内緒のオトナモード
Look at me more, an adult mode kept secret from Mom
「カワイイ」じゃ足りないの
\"Cute\" isn't enough
ワガママじゃなくちゃね
I have to be a little selfish, you know
人の波を フワリフワリ 交わりながら歩いてみる
Walking while smoothly, gently dodging the waves of people
もう少し、もう少しだけ 時間が止まればいいのに
Just a little more, just a little more, I wish time would stop
ママのペンダント 弱いネイル
Mom's pendant, pale nail polish
グラスの靴もいいけど
Glass slippers are nice, too
夢見がち おとぎ話より
Rather than daydreaming fairy tales
ドキドキが止まらない 恋もしたいな
I want to fall in love, my heart won't stop pounding
もっとあたしを見て あの子がうらやむ オトナモード
Look at me more, an adult mode that girl will envy
誰よりも先に 練習しなくちゃね
Before anyone else, I have to practice
もっとキレイになって みんながうらやむ オトナモード
Becoming even prettier, an adult mode everyone envies
この先の未来は あたしだけのモノ
The future ahead is solely mine
こんなトクベツな夜に ずっとずっと憧れてたの
I've been longing for such a special night for so long
もうすぐおうちにかえるから
Since I'll be heading home soon
今だけあたしが 主役でいいか な?
Can I be the star just for now?
もっとあたしを見て ママには内緒の オトナモード
Look at me more, an adult mode kept secret from Mom
「カワイイ」じゃ足りないの ワガママじゃなくちゃね
\"Cute\" isn't enough, I have to be a little selfish, you know
もっとキレイになって みんなに内緒の オトナモード
Becoming even prettier, an adult mode kept secret from everyone
幼い自分は お先にオヤスミ
My childish self says goodnight first
カワキヲアメク
Kawaki wo Ameku
作詞・作曲: 美波
Lyricist: Miki
未熟 無ジョウ されど 美しくあれ
Immature, heartless, but even so, be beautiful
No Destiny ふさわしくない
No destiny, it doesn't suit me
こんなんじゃきっと物足りない
Only this much is definitely not enough
くらい語っとけばうまくいく
If you just talk about it roughly, things will work out
物、金、愛、言、もう自己顕示飽きた
Things, money, love, words, I'm tired of showing off
既視感(デジャヴ)何がそんな不満なんだ?
Déjà vu! What on earth are you so dissatisfied with?
散々ワガママ語ってといって
After talking about your selfishness endlessly
これ以上他に何がいる?
What else could you possibly want beyond this?
そんなところも割と嫌いじゃない
I don't really hate that kind of side of you either
もう「聞き飽きたんだよ、そのセリフ。」
Already, \"I'm sick of hearing that line.\
中途半端だけは嫌 もういいよ
Half-heartedness is the only thing I hate, enough!
ああしてこうして言ってたって
Even if you say do this and do that
愛して どうして? 言われたって
Even if you ask, \"Why do you love me?\"
遊びだけなら簡単で
If it's just playing around, it's easy
真剣交際無茶苦茶で
Serious negotiations are a mess
思いもしない軽い言葉 何度使い果たすのか?
Thoughtless, light words, how many times are you going to wear them out?
どうせ期待してたんだ出来レースでも
Anyway, I was expecting it even if it's a fixed race
引用だらけのフレーズも
Phrases full of quotes too
踵持ち上がる言葉タブーにして
Make words that make your heels rise taboo
空気を読んだ雨降らないでよ
Please don't rain while reading the room
もどかしい話は嫌
I hate roundabout stories
必要最低限でいい
The minimum required is fine
2文字以内でどうぞ
Please give it to me in two characters or less
紅の蝶は 何のメールも送らない
The crimson butterfly doesn't send any emails
脆い扇子広げる そのほうが魅力的でしょ?
Opening a fragile folding fan, isn't that more charming?
迷いで 応えられないならほっといてくれ
If you're lost and can't answer, leave me alone
迷えるくらいなら去っていってくれ
If you're hesitant, just go away
肝心なところは筒抜けで
The crucial parts go in one ear and out the other
安心だけはさせられるような
Like giving you just enough peace of mind
甘い雨が降れば 傘もさしたくなるだろ?
If sweet rain falls, wouldn't you want to open an umbrella too?
期待したままでよかった
It was fine to keep hoping
目を瞑った 変えたかった
I closed my eyes, I wanted to change
大人ぶった 無くした 巻き戻せなかった
I acted like an adult, I lost it, I couldn't rewind
今雨、止まないで
Now rain, don't stop
未熟 無ジョウ されど 美しくあれ
Inexperienced, heartless, but still be beautiful.
No Destiny ふさわしくない
No Destiny, unfitting.
こんなんじゃきっと物足りない
With this, it's surely not enough.
くらい語りければうまくいく
If I talk about it darkly, it'll go well.
物、金、愛、言、もう自己顕示飽和
Things, money, love, words, self-display is saturated.
既視感 何がそんな不満なんだ?
Déjà vu, what are you so unsatisfied with?
散々ワガママ語ってといて
After talking so selfishly,
これ以上他に何がいる?
what else could you possibly want?
そんなところも割と嫌いじゃない
Even that part I don't really hate.
もう「聞き飽きたんだよ、そのセリフ。」
"I'm sick of hearing those lines already."
中途半端だけは嫌い もういい
I hate doing things halfway. Enough!
ああしてこうして言ってだって
Even if you say do this and that,
愛してどうして?言われてだって
or say you love me, or ask why?
遊びだけなら簡単で
It's easy if it's just for play,
真剣交渉無茶苦茶で
but serious negotiations are a mess.
思いもしない軽い言葉
Those thoughtless words,
何度使い回すのか?
just how many times will you reuse them?
どうせ期待してたんだろ出来レースでも
Anyway, you were expecting it even if it's a fixed race,
引用だらけのフレーズも
and these quote-filled phrases too.
拗ね持ち上がる言葉タブーにして
Let's make those sulking words taboo.
空気を読んだ雨降らないでよ
Read the room and don't rain, please.
まどろっこしい話は嫌い
I hate beating around the bush.
必要最低限でいい
The bare minimum is fine.
2文字以内でどうぞ
Give it to me in two characters.
紅の蝶は何のメールも送らない
The red butterfly doesn't send any mail.
脆弱扇子広げる
I spread my fragile fan,
そのほうが魅力的なんでしょう? 迷で
because you find that more attractive, right? Lost in hesitation.
応えられないならほっといてくれ
If you can't answer, leave me alone.
迷えるくらいなら去っていってくれ
If you're going to hesitate, just leave.
要心なとこは筒抜けで
The crucial parts are wide open,
安心だけはさせられるような
but like something that can give you peace of mind...
あーもう本当にんなって 素晴らしき世界
Ah, what a truly wonderful world!
んでもって今日もまた自己の醜さに呆れる
And today once again, I'm disgusted by my own ugliness.
なのに人を好きだと思う気持ちだけは
And yet, the feeling of wanting to love someone
一丁前にあるから悶えてるんでしょう
is top-notch, so I'm agonizing over it, aren't I?
ugly 正直言って私の顔は
Ugly, honestly speaking, my face
そう神様が左手で描いたみたい
is like God drew it with His left hand.
必然 この世にある ラブソングはどれ一つ
Inevitably, every single love song in this world
絶対 私向けなんかじゃないんでしょう
is definitely not meant for someone like me.
使い道のないくちづけ 憐れみを乞うに
Useless kisses, begging for pity,
スパンコールの襤褸で身を守る
protecting myself with rags of sequins.
愛されないくらいなんだ
It's just that I'm unloved.
ギラギラ輝いて私は夜を噚む
Gira-gira, shining brightly, I swallow the night.
rap tap tap tap
今に見とれろこのluv
Just you wait and see, this luv.
目に染みるは1mgの花火
Stinging my eyes is 1mg of fireworks.
drag on drag on なんてファニーこの世はビザール
Drag on, drag on, how funny, this world is bizarre.
unknown お釈迦様も存ぜぬうちに
Unknown, even before Buddha knew,
もう健やかに狂っていたみたい
it seems it was already healthily crazy.
それは世界の方か それとも私の方ですか
Is it the world's fault, or is it mine?
共生は端から無理でしょう
Coexistence was impossible from the start.
マガイモノこそかなしかれ 無我夢中疾る疾る
Imitations are sad, running frantically.
強い酸性雨が洗い流す前に
Before the strong acid rain washes it away,
蛍光色の痣抱いて
holding my fluorescent bruises,
メラメラ火を吹いて私は夜の狼
Mela-mela, blowing fire, I am the wolf of the night.
rap tap tap tap
そこで見てろこの乱舞
Watch this wild dance right there.
あー もう 本当に なんて素晴らしい世界
Ah, what a wonderfully strange world.
んで 今日もまた 己の醜さに悩む
And today once again, I'm troubled by my own ugliness.
だのに 人を好きって思う気持ちだけは 一丁前にあるから 悶えてるんですしょう
Though I'm agonizing over whether the simple urge to love someone is just around the corner.
Ugly 正直言って 私の顔は そう 神様が左手で描いたみたい
Ugly? To be honest, my face looks like it was sketched by God with his left hand.
必然 この世にあるラブソングはどれ一つ 絶対私向けなんじゃないでしょう
Inevitably, any love song in this world surely isn't meant for someone like me.
使い道のない口づけ 憐れを欲しいままに スパンコールの瘡蓋で身を守る
Begging for affection with useless kisses, hiding behind the scabs of sequins.
愛されないくらいなんだ
As if someone like me could ever be loved.
ギラギラ 輝いて私は夜を噯み Rap Tap Tap Tap 今に見とろ このluv
Shining brightly, I swallow the night, Rap Tap Tap Tap, just you wait and see my love.
目に染みるのは1mgの花火 Drag on Drag on
Soaking into my eyes is 1mg of fireworks, Drag on Drag on.
なんてファニー この世はビザール
How funny, this world is just so bizarre.
ギラ ギラ ギラ ギラ ギラ
Gira Gira Gira Gira Gira...
Unknown お釈迦様も存ぜぬうちに もう健やかに狂っていたみたい
Unknown, before even Buddha knew, it seems I'd already gone completely crazy.
それは世界の方か それとも私の方ですか 共生は端から無理でしょう
Is it the world's fault, or is it mine? Coexistence was impossible from the start.
マガイモノ ことかなしかれど 無我夢中 疾走る疾走る 強い酸性雨が洗い流す前に
Imitations are sad, running frantically before the strong acid rain washes it all away,
蛍光色の痣抱いて
hugging my fluorescent-colored bruise.
メラメラ 火を吹いて私は夜の狼 Rap Tap Tap Tap そこで見とろこの乱舞
Blazing and spitting fire, I'm a wolf of the night, Rap Tap Tap Tap, watch me dance right here.
強くおなあなたなりのmakeupで Flap up Flap up ふいに不安に
Be strong with your own makeup, Flap up Flap up, unexpectedly swallowed by anxiety.
孤独はgasoline ひだつかなし街を行く 目を閉じて もういいかい もういいかい
Loneliness is gasoline, walking down obsequious streets. Close my eyes, is this really okay?
もしも神様が左利きなら どんなに幸せか知れない
If God were left-handed, I can only imagine how happy I'd be.
ギラギラ 輝いて私は夜を噯み Rap Tap Tap Tap 今に見とろ このluv
Shining brightly, I swallow the night, Rap Tap Tap Tap, just you wait and see my love.
目に染みるのは1mgの花火 Drag on Drag on
Soaking into my eyes is 1mg of fireworks, Drag on Drag on.
なんてファニー この世はビザール
How funny, this world is just so bizarre.
ギラ ギラ ギラ ギラ ギラ
Gira Gira Gira Gira...
Give love 花は満ちて(ギラギラ) ありのままでいられない誰方もかれも
Give love, flowers are blooming. Nobody can just be the way they are.
なんて素晴らしい世界だ! ギラ付いていこう
Ah, what a wonderfully strange world! Let's shine on.
wherever you are
作詞・作曲:Taka
Lyrics & Music: Taka
I'm telling you
I softly whisper
Tonight, tonight
You are my angel
愛してるよ
I love you so
二人は一つに
We are joined as one
Tonight, tonight
I just say
Wherever you are, I'll always make you smile
Wherever you are, I'm always by your side
Whatever you say, 君を想う気持ち
Whatever you say, the feelings I hold for you
I promise you "forever" right now
I don't need a reason
I just want you, baby
Alright, alright
Day after day
この先長いことずっと
Through all the long days ahead,
どうかこんな僕とずっと 死ぬまで stay with me
please stay with me until death do us part...
We carry on
Wherever you are, I'll always make you smile
Wherever you are, I'm always by your side
Whatever you say, 君を想う気持ち
Whatever you say, the feelings I hold for you
I promise you "forever" right now
Wherever you are, I'll never make you cry
Wherever you are, I'll never say goodbye
Whatever you say, 君を想う気持ち
Whatever you say, the feelings I hold for you
I promise you "forever" right now
僕らが出会った日は 二人にとって一番目の記念すべき日だね
The day we met is our most important anniversary,
そして今日という日は 二人にとって二番目の記念すべき日だね
and today is our second most important day.
心から愛する人 心から愛しい人
The person I love from the bottom of my heart,
この僕の愛の真ん中には いつも君がいるから
at the very center of my love, you are always there.
Wherever you are, I'll always make you smile
Wherever you are, I'm always by your side
Whatever you say, 君を想う気持ち
Whatever you say, the feelings I hold for you
I promise you "forever" right now
Wherever you are
よーい！ほらあれなーっ！
Ready! Look over there!
バージョン、バージョン…あっ、なかよ バージョン、バージョン、バージョンって
Version, version... Ah, wait, "version, version, version,"
いいんか？
is that right?
やばっ、一人だから誰かツッコミが っていうのはまあいいとして、
Oh crap, since I'm alone, someone to play straight man... well, never mind that!
ということで、皆さんありがとうございました！どうだったでしょうか？
So, everyone, thank you so much! How was it?
とわでも、このステージでこのアイドル衣装をみんなに見せるのって、初めてなんだよね！どう？
Even for Towa, showing off this idol outfit on stage to everyone is a first! How is it?
やーい！
Yay!
あくまでよ、ほら、ちゃんとついているでしょ？この…
I mean, look, it's properly attached, right? This...
何これ？ (笑) ちょっと語彙力が喪失してる。
What is this? (Laughs) My vocabulary just vanished.
語彙力！おいすたー！どうでした？
Vocabulary! Oystaa! How was it?
あのね、本当、トワの…今日、トワ4月17日に、トワの1周年記念配信をしてるんですけれども、
You know, actually, Towa's... Today, April 17th, Towa is having her 1st anniversary stream,
本当は1月3日にデビューしてます。
but I actually debuted on January 3rd.
で、なんでこのちょっと日程がずれちゃったのかっていうと、トワちょっと生音で…
And why did the schedule get shifted? Well, Towa wanted to do live music...
あの8月の誕生日のときには、あの、アコースティックで生音でやって、
When it was my birthday in August, I did it acoustic with live instruments,
やっぱ生音っていいなってすごい思ったので、バンドでね、ちょっとやりたいなと。
and I thought live instruments were really great, so I wanted to do it with a band.
バンドでやりたいなって、本当にもういる、もうやってくれてるんですよ、バンド。ほら。
I wanted to do it with a band, and there are actually people who are already doing it for me, the band. Look.
本当、ありがたいしさ、ちゃんと、もうやってってもう、気持ちいいよね、やっぱりね。
Truly, I'm so grateful, and they really just go ahead and do it, it feels so good, you know.
すごいアコースティックも好評で、そう、あの、もうできることならばバンドで、ドラムと、ほら、ベースとギターと、これ生でやりたいなと。
The acoustic was also very well received, and so, if possible, with a band—drums, look, bass, guitar—I wanted to do it live.
ひゅうふうに運営さんにお願いして、「したらちょっと機材がどうしてもちょっと大がかりなんだよね」って言って、あの、じゃあ、でも、どうしてやりたいんだ、トワは。1月3日じゃなくて準備万端の時にやりますって言って、じゃあ、そうしましょうと言って、今日はね、
I asked management, and they said, "The equipment is just too massive," and I said, "Well, but I really want to do it, Towa, not on Jan 3rd, but when everything is fully prepared," and they said, "Let's do that," and so today,
この素敵な後ろでね、ほら、ずっと叩いてるでしょ？ずっと弾いてるし。それ。わあ、どうそう？生演奏に、生演奏に。そう、で、この生音でやることができましたー！もう本当にありがとうございます！皆さんのおかげです！ありがとうございます！
right behind me here, look, they've been drumming the whole time, right? And playing the whole time. That. Wow, how is it? Live performance, live performance. Yes, and we were able to do it with live sound! Thank you so much! It's all thanks to everyone! Thank you!
でもね、みんなね、Twitterとかね、見合しててもね、え、トワ様のグッズはいつ来るの？っていうふうな形でよく見たんで、よっ。
But you know, when checking Twitter and stuff, I often saw comments like, "When is Towa-sama's merch coming out?" So, yeah.
では、なんと！ありまっさ、トワの1周年グッズ発売します！どーん！
Well then, what a surprise! Arimassa, Towa's 1st anniversary goods are going on sale! Ta-da!
見て、きたー！
Look, it's here!
活動1周年記念、トワ様の記念ボイス全部セット、記念グッズ3種セット。これですね。まず、ボイスはね、まあ、聴いてもらって、記念グッズ3種セットっていうのがこちらです。
1st anniversary set: Towa-sama's commemorative voice full set, and commemorative goods 3-item set. This is it. First, for the voices, well, please listen to them, and the commemorative goods 3-item set is right here.
あ、間違えた、あ、タペストリーがこちらです。
Ah, my mistake, ah, the tapestry is right here.
じゃじゃーん！見た？どう？かわいくない？rurudoママが描いてくれたの。ママ見てるー？やーい！かわいいでしょ、これ。
Ta-da! Did you see it? How is it? Isn't it cute? rurudo mama drew this for me. Mama, are you watching? Yay! Isn't it cute?
これ何これね、ちょっと、まあ、これはちょっとあんまり、なんかみんな妄想しないでもらって。かわいいでしょ？このタペストリーと、あと、もうひとつです。どーん！
What is this, hey, well, this is a little... please don't imagine weird things, everyone. Isn't it cute? This tapestry, and also, there's one more. Ta-da!
だから、ビビのもちもちもち、もちもちのぬいぐるみクッション！
So, we have this soft, squishy Bibi plush cushion!
これな、これぐらいで、
Let's see... about this big?
わかるかな、とわの体で、これぐらいで、ね、これぐらいかな。
Can you tell against my body? Around this size.
で、すごいもちもちしてるの、もちもち。
And it's super squishy, super squishy.
もうね、これね、今しかないです、皆さん。今しかないんです。
You know, you can only get this right now, everyone. Only right now.
こちら、今しかないですよ！
Look here, it's available only now!
やばい、この格好でやるもんじゃない、今しかないですよ、はい。
Oh no, not in this outfit... but it's only available now, yep.
あの、概要欄にね、もう買えるの更新されます。
Um, the link to buy it will be updated in the description box.
でも、あと待ってくださいね、一個あるんです、どーん。
But wait, there's one more thing! Ta-da!
はい、見て、とわのモチーフデザインキーホルダー！
Look at this, the Towa-motif design keyholder!
これあれだよ、あの、これを今画像ナシなんだけど、通常のね、あの、お洋服のね、こっちにあるね、このキーホルダーがなんと！
This is... well, we don't have the image here right now, but the keyholder normally on this side of the outfit has actually...
実物になってしまいました！オーマイガッ！
become a real physical item! Oh my god!
そう、実物になっちゃったんだよ。
Yeah, it actually became a real item.
もうこれも今しかないよ、みんな！安いよ安いよ、今しかないよ、とか言って。
You can only get this now too, everyone! It's a bargain, only now, haha!
で、これを全部買ってくれた人には、特典の
And for everyone who buys the whole set, there's a special...
じゃん！イラストポストカード！とわのサイン入り！複製サイン入りのポストカードが絶対ついてくるよ！キラキラ！
Tada! An illustrated postcard! With Towa's autograph! A postcard with a replicated signature definitely comes with it!
ってことなので、ぜひどれもね、これもめちゃめちゃいいので、ぜひよろしくお願いします！
So definitely, all of these are super great, so I hope you'll check them out!
ページはね、あの今もう見れるんだけど、発売は21時配信が終わった後に
The page is viewable right now, but they go on sale right after the 9 PM stream ends,
買えるようになるので、もう海外に行くも、日本に行くも、もうもうオーバーシームみんな、とわのこと大好きでいてください！
so whether you're overseas or in Japan, everyone, please keep loving Towa a lot!
みんなちゃんとつぶやいた？これ、常闇とわ一周年記念な。つぶやいてくれた？
Did everyone tweet properly? This is Tokoyami Towa's 1st anniversary. Did you tweet about it?
つぶやいてくれたら嬉しいな。はい。
I'd be happy if you did. Yep.
ということでね、まあお水を飲んで、とわはね
So, well, having some water... Towa is...
マイペースにやっていきたいです。これからも
going to keep going at her own pace. From now on,
今までもね、マイペースにやらしてもらったんだけど、全く界隈に染まりながら、これからもとわのペースでやっていけたらと思います。みんな本当にいつもありがとう！
just like before at my own pace, while blending into the community a bit, I want to keep going at Towa's pace. Thank you all so much, always!
ということで、次ど、二つ曲聞いてください。最後の二つになります。よろしくお願いします。では、ニケさんのHearts
And with that, please listen to the next two songs. These will be the last two. Thank you. Now, niki's "Hearts"
胸の日々が星の数を告げて 輝いてまた消えるよ
The days in my heart count the stars, shining and then fading away.
思い出の中でちがいを恐れ 許されてきたはずでしょ
Fearing differences within memories, we must have been forgiven.
東の空 ビルに溶けた 風のように
Like the wind melting into the eastern building's sky...
苦しいこと 悲しいこと 消して何を唱えた
Painful things, sad things—never what was chanted...
僕が あなたが 私が あなたが
I am, you are, I am, you are...
心に刻む男 何を信じ続けて
carving into our hearts, continuing to believe in what?
感じ続けて ここに立ち焦がれてる
Continuing to feel, standing here, yearning.
今僕らは叫んで 叫んで 触れて
Right now, we are shouting, shouting, touching,
その手が縮まるほど
until those hands draw close.
いつだって聞こえた ずっと繋いで
Always heard, connected forever,
すべて心砕かれるよ
everything shatters our hearts.
幾つもの声が この空を越えて 輝いてまた消えるよ
Countless voices cross this sky, shining and then fading away.
この迷いの中で ただ意味を求め 許されてゆくはずでしょ
Seeking just meaning within this hesitation, we should be forgiven.
ヒラヒラヒラ ヒラヒラヒラ 落ちるように
Fluttering down like falling petals...
苦しいこと 悲しいこと すべて抱いて生きてきた
Painful things, sad things—I've lived embracing it all.
僕が あなたが 生まれた日から 心に刻む男
From the day I was born, the day you were born, carving into our hearts...
何を裏切られて 感じ続けて 心壊されてゆく
Being betrayed by what, continuing to feel, our hearts are breaking.
今僕らは叫んで 叫んで 触れて この目に映るほど
Right now, we are shouting, shouting, touching, until it reflects in these eyes.
風に吹かれて 誰も気づかぬように
Blown by the wind so that no one notices
区別がつかない
Can't distinguish
モノクロの世界
a monochrome world.
すべて抱いて生きてきた
Embracing everything I've lived through,
僕が あなたが 私が 君が 心に刻むんだ
I, you, I, you, carving it into our hearts.
何を信じ続けて
What should I keep believing in,
感じ続けて
keep feeling,
ここに立ち焦がれてる
standing here yearning for?
今 僕らは
Right now, we are
叫んで 叫んで 触れて
shouting, shouting, touching,
この手が滲むほど
until these hands blur—
いつだって聞こえた
I could always hear it,
すくう心の砕かれぬように
protecting my fragile heart from breaking.
風に吹かれて
Blown by the wind,
誰も気づかぬように
so that no one notices,
区別がつかない
indistinguishable
モノクロの世界
in a monochrome world.
色を足しても
Even when adding colors,
何も見えなくて
I couldn't see anything at all,
まるで私は 息を止めていた
as if I had been holding my breath.
もういいよ
It's fine now,
遠くても 叶えたい 私は
even if it's far, I want to make it happen.
こんな世界 想いも抱きしめていたいのに
In this world, I want to hold my feelings close,
夢のキャンバスに 居続ける意味はこの胸に 輝いているストーリー
the meaning of lingering on dreams shines bright—a story.
与えることに意味などないけど
There's no real meaning in giving,
拾い集めたカケラ失うの?
am I losing the fragments I gathered?
そして夜はその冷たさを
And at night, I reached out my hand
溶かして手を伸ばした
to melt away that coldness.
抱え込むここに
Holding onto this place,
意味などないけど
even if it has no meaning,
昨日は冷えた
yesterday was cold,
心失うの
will I lose my heart?
そして夜はその冷たさを
And at night, I reached out my hand
どうかして手を伸ばした もういいよ
somehow to melt away that coldness... It's fine now,
遠くても 叶えたい
even if it's far, I want to make it happen.
私は 受け止めていく 涙も
I will accept even the tears,
抱きしめていたいのに 夢のキャンバスに
even though I want to hold them close on the canvas.
ここに込めるのは この空に 描き出すストーリー
What I put into my heart here is a story drawn across the sky.
そして夜は
And at night,
その冷たさを どうかして
somehow softening that coldness,
手を伸ばした もういいよ
I reached out my hand... It's fine now,
遠くても 叶えたい
even if it's far, I want to make it happen.
私の 声なき世界 想いを
In my voiceless world, wrapping my feelings
言葉で包んだ 夢のキャンバスに
in words on the canvas of dreams,
色を足してゆく この胸に
adding colors into this heart
今 輝いて 強くなくてもいい 壊れかけてもいい
shining now. It's okay not to be strong, to break.
この心は永久(とわ)に羽ばたいて 響くように
This heart will forever soar, resonating
塗り替えてゆく パレット
and repainting the palette.
みんな
Everyone,
サンキュー！
thank you!
大好きだよ！
I love you!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
常闇トワ 1周年記念 BAND LIVE
Tokoyami Towa 1st Anniversary BAND LIVE